Everyone likes to spend time alone.
الكل يحب أن يقضي الوقت بمفرده.
I bet all of you in this room can think about a time
أراهن أنكم كلكم في هذه القاعة يمكنكم أن تفكروا بوقت ما
when all you really wanted to do was stay home alone and watch a good movie.
حين كل ما أردتم فعله حقا هو الجلوس بالمنزل ومشاهدة فيلم جيد.
I definitely can.
يمكنني ذلك بالتأكيد.
This joy we have from spending time alone is something that we all understand.
هذه الفرحة التي تنبع من قضاء الوقت بمفردك هو أمر نفهمه جميعا.
Yet, in our society nowadays,
ومع ذلك، بمجتمعنا حالياً،
it is something that is extremely stigmatized.
فهو أمر مذموم للغاية.
I'm sure you can all think about a time
أنا متأكدة من أنكم تستطيعوا أن تفكروا بلحظة
when your friends showered you with reproving looks
عندما أغرقكم أصدقاؤكم بنظرات موبخة
when you told them that, no, you weren't going to this party tonight
عندما قلت لهم، إنك لن تذهب لهذه الحفلة الليلة
because you just didn't feel like being social.
لأتك لاترغب فى التواصل إجتماعياً مع أحد.
I definitely can.
عن نفسي يمكنني ذلك بالتأكيد.
Those looks, however, managed to make us feel so guilty
هذه النظرات، تمكنت من جعلنا نشعر بالذنب
that, in the end, just a few hours later,
لدرجة، في النهاية، بعد مجرد بضع ساعات،
we find ourselves surrounded by them in a room filled with music and laughter.
نجد أنفسنا محاطين بهم بغرفة مليئة بالموسيقى والضحك.
I just want to emphasize here
أريد فقط أن أؤكد هنا
that I do not mean to say that you'd be unhappy at that party.
أنني لا أعني أن أقول أنكم لن تكونوا فرحين بالحفلة.
You may be having the time of your life. Totally amazing for you.
ربما قد تكونوا تحظون بأحلى أوقات حياتكم، مدهش تماما بالنسبة لكم.
What I do want to remind you, however,
غير أن ما أريد أن أذكركم به،
is that, initially, going to this party wasn't your first choice.
هو أن، في البداية، الذهاب لهذه الحفلة لم يكن خيارك الأول.
You wanted to stay home alone and watch a really good movie.
أردت أن تجلس بالمنزل بمفردك وتشاهد فيلما جيداً.
So, why didn't you pursue what you wanted to do?
إذا، لماذا لم تتبع ما أردت أن تفعله؟
Because you were scared of the stigma surrounding spending time alone.
لإنك كنت خائفا من الوصمة المرافقة لتمضية الوقت بمفردك.
This stigma can be summarized in an extremely simple equation:
الوصمة يمكن أن تتلخص بمعادلة بسيطة للغاية:
spending time alone equals having no friends, plus being antisocial,
تمضية الوقت بمفردك تعادل أنك لا تملك أصدقاء،
and nobody wants to be recognized as a person without friends.
ولا أحد يريد أن يُعرَف كشخص بدون أصدقاء.
This idea we all associate with spending time alone
هذه الرأي المرتبط حول قضاء الوقت بمفردنا
is so embedded in our society that we prefer conforming to the norms
مغروس بمجتمعنا لدرجة أننا نفضل الإلتزام بالرأي السائد
rather than doing the thing we truly want to do.
بدلا من القيام بالشيء الذي نريد فعله حقا.
What many people might not know, however,
غير أن، ما قد لا يعلمه أغلب الناس،
is that spending time alone is actually very beneficial.
هو أن تمضية الوقت بمفردك هو في الحقيقة مفيد للغاية.
That's why I'm standing here in front of you today,
لهذا أنا أقف أمامكم اليوم،
to prove to you that "me time" is worth fighting for.
لكي أُثْبِتَ لكم أن "وقتي الخاص" يستحق أن تحارب من أجله.
The first thing we gain from spending time alone is creativity.
أول شيء نحصل عليه من قضاء الوقت بمفردنا هو الإبداع.
As Keith Sawyer, a psychologist at WUSTL, pointed out,
كما أشار له كيث سويير، طبيب نفساني ب WUSTL،
decades of research have shown
أن عقود من الأبحاث أظهرت
that brainstorming groups of people think of far fewer ideas
العصف الذهني لمجموعات من الناس، يحظوا بأفكار أقل
than that same number of people who work alone and later pull their ideas.
من نفس عدد الأشخاص الذين يعملون بمفردهم ويشاركون أفكارهم لاحقا.
This may sound counter-intuitive
هذا يمكن أن يبدو أمرغير بديهي.
because you'd think you'd come up with more ideas
لأنك تظن أنك قد تأتي بأفكار أكثر
when surrounded by other people.
عندما تكون محاط بأشخاص آخرين.
However, if you're on your own,
غير أن، إذا كنت بمفردك،
you will allow yourself the time to formulate your own opinion on stuff
ستسمح لنفسك أن تأخد وقتاً لتكوين فكرتك الخاصة بالأمور،
and to also let your mind wander to places it probably wouldn't have gone to
وأيضا، ستطلق العنان لخيالك، لتحظى بأفكار ربما لن تحظي بها
if you had been surrounded by other people's opinions,
إذا كنت محاطا بوجهات نظر الأشخاص الآخرين،
because other people's opinions would have necessarily influenced your own.
لأنه آراء الآخرين لا بد أن تكون قد تركت تأثيرا على أفكارك.
This increased creativity we gain from spending time alone
تطور الإبداع الذي نحصل عليه نتيجة قضاء الوقت بمفردنا
has also been proven in a study done in 2012.
قد تم تأكيده في دراسة أجريت في 2012.
In this experiment, 56 adults were immersed into nature for four days,
في هذه التجربة، غمروا 56 شابا في الطبيعة لأربعة أيام،
without any form of technology.
بدون أي تكنولوجيا.
What they gained from this is that they became 50% better
ما حصلوا عليه من هذه التجربة هو أنهم أصبحوا 50% أحسن
at creative problem-solving.
بالإبداع في حل المشاكل.
So, if you allow yourself "me time," you'll become more creative.
إذن، فإذا سمحت لنفسك ب " وقتي الخاص" ستصبح أكثر إبداعا.
Pretty appealing, no?
مثير جدا، أليس كذلك؟
Another bonus point we get from spending time alone
نقطة إضافية نحصل عليها من خلال تمضية الوقت بمفردنا
is that it makes us work harder.
هو أنه يجعلنا نعمل جاهدين.
We always have a tendency to do less when we're surrounded by other people.
لدينا دائما نزعة للعمل بشكل أقل عندما نكون محاطين بأشخاص آخرين.
I mean, teachers, there's a reason why students love group work,
ما أقصد، أيها المعلمون، هناك سبب لما يحب التلاميذ مجموعات العمل،
or at least part of them.
أو على الأقل، جزء منهم.
I don't know if you've noticed,
لا أعلم إن لاحظتم،
but when you say "group work," half of the class looks like this -
ولكن عندما تقول "مجموعة عمل" نصف القسم يبدو هكذا -
and the other half, like this.
والجزء الآخر، هكذا.
You can probably guess who's going to end up doing all the work in the end.
يمكنك، التخمين من سيقوم بكل العمل فعلاً في النهاية.
This tendency we have to work less when surrounded by other people
هذا الميل للعمل بشكل أقل عندما نكون محاطين بأناس آخرين
has been termed "social loafing" by Max Ringelmann.
أطلق عليه "التسكع الاجتماعي" بواسطة ماكس ربنجلمان.
In the 1890s, this guy set up a study
سنة 1890، هذا الشخص قام بدراسة
in which he made an increasing amount of people pull on a rope.
حيث جعل عددا متزايدا من الناس يسحبوا حبل.
In each of his experiments,
في كل من تجاربه،
he measured the effort each person pulled on the rope.
قام بقياس كل مجهود قام به كل شخص في سحب الحبل.
What we can see on this graph is that the more people were in each group
ما يمكن أن نراه في هذا البيان هو أن كلما زاد عدد الناس في كل مجموعة
the less force each individual person exerted.
كلما قل الجهد المبذول من طرف كل شخص.
So, if allow yourself "me time," you'll work harder.
إذن، إذا سمحت لنفسك ب "وقتي الخاص" ستعمل بجد أكثر.
And if this doesn't convince you enough,
وإن هذا لم يقنعك كفاية،
just think about spending time alone and sleep.
فكر فحسب بقضاء الوقت بمفردك والنوم.
And who doesn't love sleep?
ومن لا يحب النوم؟
Because, honestly, that's basicaly what it is.
لأنه، صراحة، هذا هو أساس الأمر.
When you sleep, you take the time to recharge before you start another day.
عندما تنام، تأخد الوقت لتشحن قبل أن تبدأ يوما آخرا.
When you spend time alone, you take the time to recharge
عندما تقضي الوقت بمفردك، تأخد الوقت لتشحن طاقتك مجدداً
from all your social interactions.
من جميع تفاعلاتك الاجتماعية.
Alone time and sleep seem really similar to me.
الوقت الإنفرادي والنوم كلاهما يبدو سواء بالنسبة لي.
So, to summarize,
إذن، الخلاصة،
spending time alone will make you more creative,
تمضية الوقت بمفردك يجعلك أكثر إبداعا،
will make you work harder and can be regarded as sleep.
يجعلك تعمل بجهد أكثر ويمكن أن يعتبر كالنوم.
Those reasons seem all really good ones to stay in.
تلك الأسباب تبدوا كلها جيدة للبقاء في البيت.
There however remains one tiny thing
على أية حال، يبقى هناك أمر صغير
that prevents us from spending the time alone that we need.
الذي يمنعنا من إمضاء ما نحتاجه من الوقت بمفردنا.
And I'm not talking about the stigma surrounding it.
وأنا لا أتكلم عن الوصمة التي تحيط بها،
I'm talking about this thing called FOMO, or "fear of missing out."
أنا أتكلم عن ما يسمى "فومو"، أو " الخوف من تفويت شيء ما "
You've probably heard of it already.
ربما قد سمعت بها من قبل.
You know, it's that feeling you get when you're invited to a party,
إنه هذا الشعور الذي تحس به عندما تُدعى لحفلة،
but all you really want to do is stay home alone.
و لكن كل ما تريد فعله هو الجلوس بمفردك بالمنزل.
Yet, you still go because, otherwise,
وتذهب رغم ذلك، وإلا،
you're scared that you won't belong to the "cool group" anymore.
فإنك خائف من ألا تنتمي "للمجموعة الرائعة" بعد ذلك.
However, I hope that, after having listened to my [TEDx] talk,
على أية حال، أتمنى أنه، بعدما تشاهدوا حديثي TEDx
you will understand that spending time alone is actually really beneficial.
ستفهمون أنه قضاء الوقت بمفردك هو مفيد فعلا.
So, stop feeling scared and guilty
إذن، كفى من الشعور بالخوف وتأنيب الضمير،
if you don't want to be around other people.
إن لم تكن ترغب في أن تكون برفقة أناس آخرين،
You have all the reasons to. Thank you very much.
لك كل الأسباب لذلك. شكرا جزيلا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)